Beau Hale

Web Developer

San Diego, CA | 818-726-2139 | halebeau3@gmail.com

Linkedin | Github | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Experienced front end and full stack developer. I am a bootcamp graduate with an extensive background in various coding languages, developing websites, apps, and building projects from the ground up. Detail-oriented and design mindset from 20+ years of experience in the salon industry. I also have an interest in UI/UX, which ensures that my websites and apps are both beautiful and user-friendly.

SKILLS

FRONT END: HTML, CSS, Javascript, React.js, React Native, React Hooks, Redux, jQuery.

BACK END: Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, Ruby on Rails.

OTHER: Git, GitHub, NPM, Yarn, RESTful APIs, Vercel, Heroku, Netlify, Firebase, test-driven development, Mocha + Chai. AGILE methodologies.

PROJECTS

BARBER SITE [demo | Github]

- Created a stylish website for a Barber Shop with HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap, Netlify, Git, Material UI.
- Used flex, grid, custom CSS, carousels, media queries, custom Javascript, is mobile-first and responsive.

RESTAURANT SITE [demo | Github]

- Created a clean restaurant website with HTML, CSS, Netlify, Git...
- Built with HTML, CSS only.

FLASHCARD-O-MATIC [demo | Github]

- Built application that allows users to create, study, and edit flashcards for educational purposes.
- Utilized React hooks to build SPA using single-purpose components and read-only props.
- Developed full stack app using NPM, JSX and React.

EXPERIENCE

LEAD INSTRUCTOR Dec 2021- May 2022

LEARN Academy | San Diego

- Aligned with Educational team to plan out cohort curriculum.
- Created custom full stack lessons and lectures.
- Coordinated with Associate Intstructor to implemented lessons.
- Led a cohort of 20+ students through full stack languages and technologies.
- Used AGILE methodologies and best practices for consistent workflows.

WEB DEVELOPER Jan - Apr, 2021

MyRoadmap | San Diego

- Aligned with dev team on the company website and migration to Mobile App using React/React Native..
- Created custom CSS design and utilized Asana for workflow.
- Implemented React and Python logic in mobile designs.
- Assisted Senior Developer on building a cross-platform app for company success.

WEB DEVELOPER | QA SPECIALIST

Mar 2020 - Mar 2021

SunnyByte - Software Development Firm | Los Angeles

- Collaborated with senior devs to develop projects for websites throughout phases of the project's life cycle.
- Maintained existing code and functionality during migration into ongoing operations of web businesses.
- Developed cross-browser and cross-device compatibility in graded browser super environment.
- Helped in the development and QA departments of all websites and apps including Gelson's and Hyundai.

EDUCATION

THINKFUL | thinkful.com Apr 2021 - Dec 2021

Bootcamp - Software Engineering Immersive

Remote full stack development program.

Designed mobile-first full stack applications from conception to deployment, learning industry best practices.
 NUCAMP | nucamp.co

Nov 2019 - Apr 2020

Bootcamp - Front End Web Development + Mobile Design

- Remote full stack + Mobile development program.
- Designed Mobile-first and cross-platform web applications using React/React Native.
- Created projects from inception to developing a Minimum Viable Product (MVP) and moved it to large-scale implementation.

SKILLCRUSH | skillcrush.com

July 2019 - Nov 2019

Certificate - Front End Development

- Online front end web development program.
- Developed front end, Mobile-first websites.

TEAM TREEHOUSE | teamtreehouse.com

June 2020 - Jan 2021

Certificate - Front End Development

- Online front end web development program, focused on Web design, development tools and languages.
- Developed front end, Mobile-first websites.
- Created cross platform projects.